Carpenter Demetria

512 Eisenhower Drive, Tyler Texas 75704 Home: 903-714-8206 - dj.2326@hotmail.com

Professional Summary

Meticulous Medical laboratory technician experienced in performing techniques like gram stains, osmometry and coagulation assessments. Well-organized and disciplines with methodical approach to handling specimens and conducting tests. Prepared to offer nine years' experience in the field to new position with room for advancement.

Licenses

ASCP certification 82818

Skill Highlights

- Accomplished in hematology
- Serology knowledge
- Laboratory diagnostic equipment
- Sample checking
- Excellent lab practices
- Rapid tests (Strep A, Influenza, and RSV)
- Quality control procedures
- Clinical assays proficiency
- · Test result validity verification

- Accomplished in Chemistry
- Accomplished in Phlebotomy
- Accomplished in Blood Bank

Professional Experience

Medical Laboratory Technician- Transfusion Service

April 2019 to Current

South Bend Medical Foundation Inc. — South Bend, IN

- Prepared specimens for analysis and established proper chronological priorities in testing
- Recorded patients' medical history, vital statistics and test results in electronic medical records
- Evaluated accuracy and compliance of all documentation and reports
- Maintained clean and fully operational laboratory equipment

Medical Laboratory Technician

September 2016 to January 2019

TEXAS ONCOLOGY — TYLER, TEXAS

- Maintained clean and fully operational laboratory equipment
- Cleaned and sterilized lab area, tools and equipment
- Followed laboratory guidelines for handling biological specimens
- Performed , chemistry analysis, urinalysis and hematology
- Prepared specimens for analysis and established proper chronological priorities in testing
- Recorded patients' medical history, vital statistics and test results in electronic medical records

Medical Laboratory Technician

August 2011 to March 2017

East Texas Medical Center — Tyler, Texas

- Followed strict aseptic techniques to protect patients when collecting blood and tissue samples
- Cleaned and sterilized lab area, tools and equipment
- Recorded control values from technical instruments to maintain reliability and validity of test results
- Actively maintained up-to-date knowledge of applicable state and Federal laws and regulations
- Followed laboratory guidelines for handling biological specimens
- Maintained clean and fully operational laboratory equipment
- Managed departmental inventory and supply ordering

Education and Training

Associate of Science: Medical Laboratory Technician, 2011

Tyler Junior College — Tyler, Texas, United States

REFERENCES

KILBASE, ANDREA
SOUTH BEND MEDICAL FOUNDATION
574-210-7083
WITUCKI, KIM
SOUTH BEND MEDICAL FOUNDATION
574-274-7423
CARAWAY, TAMMY
EAST TEXAS MEDICAL CENTER
903-531-8122
ROUSSEAU, AMANDA
EAST TEXAS MEDICAL CENTER
903-714-0765
HERNDON, DEVONA
TEXAS ONCOLOGY
903-258-3598